Benjamin Nicholson

🖫+64-020-4059-3898 | Benjaminnicholson.work@gmail.com

in Ben Nicholson | BenCNicholson

Christchurch, New Zealand

ABOUT

Hi! I'm Ben. A 22 year old, recent Computer Science graduate from the University of Otago with a passion for software development. I am eager to apply my programming skills and technical expertise in an entry-level developer role that offers opportunities for growth and challenge.

EDUCATION

University of Otago

2021 - 2024

Bachelor of Science - Computer Science

Dunedin, New Zealand

Subjects include: Relational Databases, Visual Computing, Software Engineering, Cloud Computing, Data Structures and Algorithms, Web Development & Computer Systems.

• St Bede's College NCEA Levels 1, 2, & 3 2016 - 2020

Christchurch, New Zealand

EXPERIENCE

• New Zealand Defence Force

November 2023 - present

Reservist, Royal New Zealand Army Medical Corps

New Zealand

As a reserve combat medic in the New Zealand Army, I gained expertise in advanced first aid and the art of soldiering. Expanding my ability to adapt under pressure, communicate effectively and work in diverse teams. The military has contributed significantly to my personal growth. Fostering resilience and a lead-self approach to my work and life.

- Teamwork
- Resilience.
- o First aid.

• New World
Checkout Supervisor, New World Gardens

April 2022 - July 2024

New Zealand

Whilst studying at university, I had the opportunity to work as a checkout supervisor. This role involved managing people, locking up the store and, importantly, interacting with customers. By doing all these tasks my confidence and interpersonal skills were dramatically improved.

- · Leadership.
- Interpersonal skills.
- · Communication.

PROJECTS

• Cavern: A terminal based Rogue-like Dungeon Crawler. Coded in standard library C++.

July 2024 - October 2024

Tools: C++, Git, Github, CI/CD, Code Coverage, Static Analysis, Agile & Scrum.

y 2024 - October 2024

- Developed A* Search for Enemy Movement.
- Implemented ANSI RGB for our terminal display, achieving a better GUI.
- Created UML Diagrams, ensuring clear execution of our ideas.
- Applied Code Coverage tools to analyze our projects unit test coverage.

SKILLS

- **Programming Languages:** Java (Intermediate), C++ (Intermediate), SQL (Intermediate), Javascript (Beginner), HTML & CSS.
- **Database Systems:** MySQL & MariaDB.
- Cloud Technologies: AWS, Vagrant (Beginner), Terraform (Beginner)
- DevOps & Version Control: Git (Intermediate), Github & Gitlab.
- o Other Tools & Technologies: Bash, Docker & Virtual Box.
- Soft Skills: Teamwork, Communication, Approachable, Resilient & Adaptable.
- Other: Advanced First Aid.

LEADERSHIP EXPERIENCE

• Checkout Supervisor

New World

April 2022 - July 2024



- Supervised over fifteen staff members.
- Improved the morale of the team.
- Assisted in the creation of a social netball team.

ADDITIONAL INFORMATION

Interests: Tramping, Personal Fitness, Avid Reader & Getting out of my comfort zone.